HARRIET THOMPSON

A web developer with an analytical background in fashion buying and merchandising. I am excited to bring my experience of creative problem solving, analysis and team management into my new career in Web Development. I really enjoy working in a diverse team and pride myself on being a fast learner with a flexible attitude.

In addition to coding, I enjoy playing the drums and the violin, and spending as much time outdoors as possible, either hiking, skiing or camping.

PROJECTS

PINIT! May 2019

Pinit! is a full stack web application built with Node, Express, jQuery, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS and SASS. This app stores and displays learning resources as images and URLs.

Tweeter May 2019

Tweeter is a simple AJAX-based, single-page Twitter clone using jQuery, HTML and CSS.

TinyApp May 2019

TinyApp is a full stack web application built with Node and Express that allows a user to shorten long URLs.

EXPERIENCE

Oak + Fort

Production Manager, April 2017- April 2019

As Production Lead I was responsible for managing and training three Junior members of our team. I oversaw the production timeline, from sampling to delivery, while working closely with the design, sourcing and logistics teams. I managed our supplier network to ensure that good quality products met production timelines and margin targets. I reported these elements along with sales analysis to influence future buys for the coming seasons.

Topshop - Arcadia Group

Merchandising Assistant, May 2014-Sept 2016

During my time in the Merchandising team I analysed sales data to discover trends and influence decisions on future buys. I assisted in planning and forecasting trade in season, by flagging risk and opportunity and managing stocks accordingly. I analysed lessons learnt at the end of each season to streamline buying decisions in the future. I Managed and trained three juniors in our team.

Eighty Sixth Floor Music

Digital Marketing and Social Media Manager, Sept 2012- May 2014

As Digital Marketing and Social Media Manager I wrote content for the company's website, gained a good understanding of SEO and used Google Analytics and Adwords to analyse audience needs and predict trends.

Telephone: 236-999-6256 harrietrsthompson@gmail.com LinkedIn: harriet-thompson-32925663/

github: github/hazthompson

SKILL STACK

Languages & Frameworks

- HTML/CSS/SASS
- JavaScript
- Node.js
- React
- jQuery
- Bootstrap

Systems & Databases

- Git/GutHub
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL

EDUCATION

Web Development Bootcamp

Lighthouse Labs

A full-time web development bootcamp, covering topics such as javascript, Node.js, React, Ruby, HTML/CSS, MongoDB and PostgreSQL. This programme emulates a developers' work environment through a variation of individual exercises, pair programming and group projects.

University of Durham

Combined Honours in History & English Literature 2:1